Juan Antonio Casillas Aguiar

Querétaro, Querétaro, Mexico

casillas51@gmail.com

(442) 747 9659

linkedin.com/in/antoniocasillas

Summary

I have more than 15 years of experience working on IT. I like to know new technologies or new solutions, I'm an expert on Java. I managed multidisciplinary teams made up of developers, analysts, testers to cascade projects based on CMMi, PMP and Agile methodology as Scrum and Kanban.

I am self-taught and I like to learn new technologies any time

Experience



Senior Java Engineer

Tata Consultancy Services

Apr 2022 - Present (1 year 11 months)

Development of Rest Full Java microservices for cloud applications. The following technologies are used: Spring Boot, Spring Security, Spring Cloud and Azure Cloud for the protection of code repositories and CI/CD tools

Development of unit tests which must have 90% code coverage in order to authorize their release in a production environment.

Daily and weekly report of activities based on the Agile methodology with Scrum and Kanbam Release new micro services into AWS environment and maintain string connections with Spring Cloud



NonSAP Latm Lead

Wipro

Oct 2020 - Apr 2022 (1 year 7 months)

Manage non sap applications for Latin America based on Java technologies and Cognos. Bring support to users validating configurations and the status of each server. Build new microservices based on Spring Boot and Rest full technology. Deploy microservices on AWS environments and configure each connection with a single Spring Cloud Service.



Full Stack Developer

Codigo Fuente Software Development

Jun 2019 - Mar 2020 (10 months)

Full stack developer of Medtrainer application. My activities were developer new microservices based on Rest full technologies to create new features for web application based on Angular. Bring support to issue reported by help desk and created unit test to validate any new issue and fixed it.

• Lead Java Developer

Openpay México

Sep 2018 - Mar 2019 (7 months)

Manage java develop team to create new features and attend issues from the help desk team. I work over Open Pay application, validating the security of each new feature and reviewing every single

commit to ensure the security and quality of the application. openpay.com is an application to pay online, so I was in charge to validate every change to avoid security flaws.

Project Manager and Scrum Master

Dextra Technologies a Deloitte business

Mar 2016 - Aug 2018 (2 years 6 months)

I managed the development of several Java, PHP and C# projects. I was responsible for following the PMI guidelines and I was an artifact owner for CMMi structure. I ensured the compliance of the Scrum activities. I helped the financial area to project the budget for every period required for my area and ensure to report every new financial event to consider for the next period.

Project Lead Software Development

Solser

Oct 2011 - Jan 2016 (4 years 4 months)

I handled several Java projects, from the interview with the new client to define the work to be done to deliver the project and get the client's approval. I oversaw grooming new hires and teaching internal staff to assist in daily activities. I managed the databases and repositories servers for all develop teams, also I implement my first project with continuous integration using Jenkins

Technical Lead Java

Stefanini LATAM

Mar 2009 - Sep 2011 (2 years 7 months)

I collaborated in project to update Banco Galicia's teller system (Oracle Siebel Teller) managing the develop team to finish the first release on time, provided technical support to team and kept in contact with customer to identify new requirements. I started working as a Java Sr Developer and I was promoted to Technical Leader three months after my arrival in Argentina, due to the way I work and the communication I had with all my teammates.

Senior Software Developer

Stefanini Brasil

Sep 2007 - Mar 2009 (1 year 7 months)

As a developer, I worked on several projects with the Java, EJB and Spring XML. I helped my team to develop a new application for call center to manage the incoming calls from the customer. I worked for an insurance company creating web services client to get the insured information and create new events from a desktop application with Java Swing

Al finalizar el proyecto fui asignado a la celula de Argentina para participar en un proyecto mas grande.



Java Web Developer

Banco Azteca

Jan 2006 - Aug 2007 (1 year 8 months)

I worked as Java developer, creating new web applications to manage the sales from each branch office of Banco Azteca. I designed a new front component based on Java Swing to present all information to the user

Education

Instituto Tecnológico de Querétaro

Licenciatura, Ingeniería en Sistemas Computacionales 2000 - 2006

Licenses & Certifications

Scrum Fundamentals Certified - VMEdu Inc. 554820

Scrum Master Certified - VMEdu Inc. 592158

PHPUnit: Testing with a Bite - SymfonyCasts

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals - Microsoft 1359-8588

Skills

Java EE • Project Management • Project Estimation • Project Planning • Integración continua • Spring Framework • Oracle Database • Eclipse • Maven • Hibernate